Yohei Suzuki

Profile

High skilled Japanese and English Translator, Localization Coordinator, Online Marketing Analyst, Community Manager and Performance Marketing Manager. Familiar with technical project, having affinity and passion of IT and new technology. Positive thinker with problem solving and analytical skill, Multitask worker. Highly motivated and interested for learning new computer software and new skills.

Contact

getsal030@gmail.com +49 176 3137 0648

Obentrautstr 43 10963

Berlin Germany

Skills

Language

- Japanese Native
- English Fluent
- German Working level

Skill

- User Research
- Google AD certification
- HTML & CSS
- AB testing
- Usebility testing

Tools

- MS Office (Excel, Word, Power point)
- · Trados, Memo Q
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- · Google AD editor
- Google Analytics

Experience

PPC Manager 2017-Present

Peak Ace AG, Berlin

Support with the creation and optimization of paid search campaigns, keyword research and the creation and optimization of ad copies, conduct competitor analyses for clients from various industries, support with the creation of reports and interpretation of KPIs.

Translator, Localization Manager.....2007-Present **Freelance**

Able to translate 2k-3k words per day for complex contents. Managing, budget controlling entire life cycle of localization, translation and proofreading projects. Staffing freelance vendors, preparing project documentations, quality management, account management and acquire customers. Worked for several company via agencies and direct deal, include:

Google, Amazon.com, Intel, Booking.com (Average 20k+ words per week), Spotify.com (Launching contents), EBEL, Wonderfulexpo2015.info (Italian tourism site), Philips, and many more.

Online Media Analyst 2015-2016

Gorkana - Freelance

Provide analytics report of specific brand on online and offline media with using analytics tools.

Community Online Marketing Manager ----- 2010-2013 Swerford holdings - Gibraltar

Working as a Community Manager for Marketing, Localization for 19 Multilingual website called pokerstrategy.com, which has huge table of contents with fast paced start up environment. The Company is very successful affiliate marketing company, have gained very outstanding affiliate marketing knowledge and extensive community management skill.

Education

Economics, Kanto Gakuin University, Japan 2000-2004

Web Master Course, Digital Hollywood technical school, 2007

iOS Swift Developer course, Tech:Camp, 2016

Customer Support Representative ------2009-2010

888.com, Gibraltar

Providing support service to the members via email, phone and live chat on arrange of issues; such as game enquiries, helping with deposits, cashing out of funds etc in English and Japanese. Archived 20+ support issues to be solved per day. Also offering up sell to get deposit from the members. Translating Japanese to English and vice versa for the Support Department, and any other department in the company.

Technical / Service Support 2007-2008 Hi-bit K.K and N.T.T, Tokyo

Provided support service to the customers via email, phone, on a range of issues; such as Technical issues, service issues, handling customer's complaints, pressing overdue payments. Also responsible for upsell campaign.

Label Manager, Festival Director—2001-2006 Label Manager, Festival Director—Tokyo

Label Manager, Festival Director~ Led a team to achieve festival success. Greatly influenced the market by indoor event "Stargate" & outdoor festival " Utage", which had audiences count up to 5000.

- ~CD, Vinyl Distributor~ Distributed music media as CDs, and vinyl for a Japanese market, Find new artist and bring in a boom.
- ~Media Design & Promotion~ Created a media design for a flyer, album cover, website